intheswim.com 2014-07-03

# Help - Get Help With Your In the Swim Order or Product

  * Ordering Help
  * Contact Us
  * Information About Your Order
  * Payment Information
  * Returns & Exchanges
  * Search Tips
  * Security & Privacy
  * Shipping & Tax Information

  * Online Ordering Process
  * Customer Comments
  * Are All Products In The Catalog Found On The Website?
  * Can I Order Products From Your Website Or Catalog over The Phone?
  * Can I Fax Or Mail In My Order?
  * How Do I Request A FREE Copy Of Your Catalog?
  * How Do I Get Discount Offers Via Email?

Return to Help Index

1\. Select a product category from the side bar, or enter either a product name or product number in the search field at the top left side of the website pages and then click "Search."

2\. From the list of product categories, which are displayed under the Store heading, click on the product categories that you are interested in viewing.

3\. You will now be able to view all products and corresponding product photos with a product description. Click on any product photo to enlarge photo and view detailed product information.

4\. If you wish to order a product, enter the desired quantity in the box to the left of the product number. Click on "Add To Cart" button to the right of the products name. Your shopping cart will open on the next page displaying the product has been added to your cart. You may continue check out by clicking the "Check Out Now" button.

5\. If you wish to order another product and continue to shop, repeat steps #1-4 above.

6\. On the next screen you can either log in or continue as a guest and create your account after you place the order. That is where you put in your bill to and ship to information. You will then be directed to the Check Out Page where you will be able to view your order information, and enter all your payment information.

7\. Click "Place Order" to begin processing your order or you may choose to continue shopping and check out later.

8\. If you choose to Place order, you will then have a page displaying confirmation of your order. Any special coupons that did not validate at check out, will validate here, and your order will be recalculated and confirmed.

9\. Please be sure to include your phone number so that we may contact you if there are questions regarding your order.

**Note:** All items and prices are subject to verification during processing. You will be contacted prior to the final completion of your order if a situation requires attention. In The Swim is not responsible for inadvertent misprints or errors.

Return to Ordering Help

Please write any special requests or questions you have regarding your order in the “Customer Comments” field of the checkout page. All comments are manually reviewed prior to placing your order, and a representative can contact you to answer your questions.

Return to Ordering Help

Yes. If you would like to use your catalog as a reference when placing your order, Order by Item Number to quickly add items to your shopping cart without having to browse the site for them.

There is a bigger selection of products on the website than there is in the printed catalog. The website features our full line of products year-round, as well as a Clearance section with discontinued and “scratched & dented” merchandise. 

Return to Ordering Help

Of course! Just call, 24 hours a day:

  * Residential pools: 1-800-288-7946
  * Commercial pools: 1-800-765-7946
  * Spas: 1-800-288-7946

Note: “Internet Only” prices apply only to orders processed online.

Return to Ordering Help

Of Course! You can print out your completed “Checkout” page and fax To: 1-800-766-5329. A valid credit card number is required for faxed orders.

Mail orders to: In The Swim, 320 Industrial Drive, West Chicago, IL 60185 Attn: WEB. Please either include a check for payment or a valid credit card number and your signature.

Return to Ordering Help

To receive a FREE catalog Click Here to provided your mailing information.

Return to Ordering Help

If you are not already receiving email specials from In The Swim, Sign Up Now! You will receive special discounts and offers exclusively for our internet customers.

Return to Ordering Help

* * *

  * About Us
  * Email Us
  * Call Us
  * Fax Us
  * Write Us
  * Do You Have A Retail Store?
  * How Do I Apply For A Job At In The Swim?

Return to Help Index

In The Swim was founded in 1982 by a husband and wife team. Shipping chlorine from the back of their garage and taking orders on their front porch, they began to have a vision that this could be something big.

As the quantities of their orders increased, so did the loyalty of their customers. Before long, In The Swim relocated to a larger facility and hired their first employees to answer the phone. As In The Swim’s customers grew in number, so did the product selection.

The one constant factor of In The Swim’s growth has been maintaining the highest level of customer satisfaction through its dedication to quality products at the best possible prices and its commitment to the highest level of customer service.

Return to Contact Us

Every effort is made to respond to your email questions personally within 48 hours, and in most instances, we will respond even sooner than that. If you would like an immediate answer to your question, please call us at 1-800-288-7946.

[drpool@intheswim.com](mailto:drpool@intheswim.com) \- For general questions regarding care for your pool or spa, product-related questions or comments and questions about parts for your pool equipment.

[customerservice@intheswim.com](mailto:customerservice@intheswim.com) customerservice@intheswim.com - For credits, returns, adjustments, product warranties, rebates, order status information and shipping questions.

[webmaster@intheswim.com](mailto:webmaster@intheswim.com) \- For technical website problems, questions or suggestions

Return to Contact Us

In The Swim is open 24 hours a day, 7 days a week for your convenience.

  * Residential pools: 1-800-288-7946
  * Commercial pools: 1-800-765-7946
  * Spas: 1-800-288-7946

Return to Contact Us

  * Residential pools: 1-800-766-5329
  * Commercial pools: 1-800-448-7329
  * Spas: 1-800-766-5329

Return to Contact Us

In The Swim 320 Industrial Drive West Chicago, IL 60185 

Return to Contact Us

Yes! We have a warehouse outlet located in West Chicago, Illinois (located in the western suburbs about 40 miles west of downtown Chicago) as a courtesy to customers in the local area. You can purchase any item sold in our catalog or on our website at the warehouse outlet.

**Location:** 320 Industrial Drive, West Chicago IL 60185   
**Directions:** Route 59 to Route 38 West to Kress North to Downs East to Industrial North to 320. Plenty of free parking!   
**Hours:** We are now open Monday thru Friday - 9:00am - 7:00pm, Saturday & Sunday - 9:00am - 4:00pm. 

Please call our store at (630)-876-0040 to check stock, or for a fast & friendly answer to any of your pool or spa needs! 

Return to Contact Us

We are always seeking dynamic, assertive individuals with the energy and leadership that will continue to make our company a leader in the pool supply industry. If you offer exceptional qualities and have a desire to succeed, you can explore opportunities by sending your resume to (no phone calls please):

Mail To:  
In The Swim  
320 Industrial Drive  
West Chicago, IL 60185  
Attn: Human Resources  
Fax to: 1-630-876-1091

Click Here For Current Positions

Employees of In The Swim enjoy a comprehensive benefits package, including medical and dental coverage, as well as life insurance programs, merchandise discounts and more. In The Swim is committed to equal opportunity employment and encourages applications from people of diverse backgrounds. 

Return to Contact Us

* * *

  * Has My Order Been Processed Or Shipped?
  * When Will I Receive My Order?
  * There Was A Problem With My Shipment, How Do I Get It Corrected?

Return to Help Index

Orders are processed the same day they are received. If you have received an Order Confirmation from us, then your order has been processed. In-Stock orders placed Monday-Friday by 4pm CST are shipped the same day the order is processed. Please allow 2 additional days for delivery when placing an order on a holiday. Items that are on backorder or have other special shipping requirements are indicated next to the product listing.

If you need to make a change on an order you have placed, it is best to call us as soon as possible at 1-800-288-7946. Have your Order Number available for the operator. We will make every effort to change your order as requested, but it is possible that your order may have already shipped and further action may be required to correct it.

Return to Information About Your Order

In-stock orders placed Monday-Friday by 4pm CST are shipped the same day, and should arrive within 2-4 days. Please allow 2 additional days when placing an order on a holiday. Estimated delivery dates for backordered items and items requiring special shipping are noted next to the product listing.

Return to Information About Your Order

When inquiring about your order, please have your order information on hand:

  * Full name and address of the person the order is billed
  * Order number that you received in your “order confirmation email”
  * Customer number (if available).

You can call customer service to resolve any problems or concerns with your order:  
1-800-374-1500

You also can contact us anytime via our e-mail address: [customerservice@intheswim.com](mailto:customerservice@intheswim.com) If you are not satisfied with your order, please return it in new condition within 30 days of purchase. Please see our Returns & Exchanges section for guidelines. 

Return to Information About Your Order

* * *

  * What Forms Of Payment Do You Accept?
  * How Can I Place An Order If I Don’t Have A Credit Card?
  * Can I Get A Gift Receipt?
  * Easy-Pay Payment Plans

Return to Help Index

  * Credit Cards: Master Card, Visa, Discover, American Express
  * Debit Cards: (deducts from your bank account) Master Card and Visa labels only at this time
  * Personal Checks (through the mail only)
  * Money Orders (through the mail only)
  * Travelers Checks (through the mail only)

Return to Payment Information

You can print out your completed “checkout” page and mail it to us with a personal check, money order or traveler’s checks.

Mail to: In The Swim   
320 Industrial Drive   
West Chicago, IL 60185   
Attn: WEB

All returned checks are re-presented. All returned checks are subject to reasonable fees, collections charges and attorney fees if necessary.

Return to Payment Information

Currently, In The Swim does not offer gift receipts. If you are unsure of what to purchase as a gift, why not give a gift certificate and let the recipient choose exactly what they want? Click Here To Purchase A Gift Certificate

Return to Payment Information

Financing Disclosures Easy-Pay Payment Plans: Offered on select designated items throughout our website or catalogs for Credit Card Orders Only. Extended payments are available subject to credit approval for terms as determined solely by In The Swim for periods no longer than six (6) months. Interest is at 0% with the Annual Percentage Rate determined by the amount financed and term which includes an initial service fee of $9.95 added to the initial payment and fees of $4.95 per month until the amount is paid in full. The monthly payments shall be of equal amounts plus the$9.95 fee with the first payment due upon acceptance of the order and $4.95 per month until paid in full. Example, the first month payment at the time of order will be the amount of the order divided by 6 plus $9.95 and monthly payments two through 6 will include the fee of $4.95 plus 1/6th of the order amount. If the Order amount is $1200.00, monthly payments would be: month 1 upon acceptance of order $200.00 plus $9.95, months 2 through 6 $200.00 plus $4.95, for an Annual Percentage Rate of 9.8472%.

Installment payment plans in default will immediately become collectible in full. All returned checks are represented. All returned checks and payment plans in default are subject to reasonable fees, collections charges and attorney fees, if necessary.

Return to Payment Information

* * *

  * 30-Day Guarantee
  * Returns For Custom Orders
  * Return Procedure

Return to Help Index

If you are not completely satisfied with your purchase, you may return it (in new condition) for any reason within 30 days for a complete refund of the purchase price of the product and sales tax, if applicable. Please call Customer Service at 1-800-374-1500 to initiate the return process. We are unable to credit you for handling charges. Charges for shipping returned products back to us are your responsibility. We will exchange or refund your purchase, as you request. Please allow 21 business days from the date you return your package for your refund to be credited or your exchange to be completed.

Return to Returns & Exchanges

Returns on custom orders will be accepted for manufacturing defects only.

Return to Returns & Exchanges

Please fill out the return form on the back of the original invoice sent with your product and send it along with your return to the address below via USPS (be sure the package is insured for the full value), UPS or Federal Express. Packages must be insured and prepaid for delivery. In The Swim is not responsible for return shipment or if products are lost in transit of the return:

In The Swim   
320 Industrial Drive   
West Chicago, IL 60185   
ATTN: RETURNS DEPT.

Return to Returns & Exchanges

* * *

  * How Can I Find Clearance Items?
  * How Can I Find A Product That Is In Your Catalog?
  * Browsing Categories
  * Using The SEARCH Field

Return to Help Index

Click on Clearance (found on the side navigation bar and on the home page) for permanently reduced prices on discontinued items, overstock items, returned merchandise and “scratch & dented” merchandise.

Return to Search Tips

If you know the item number of the product, you can find it two ways: Enter the item number in the search field to locate the product on our website or use the “Order by Item Number” function to begin adding items into your shopping cart. If you do not know the item number, enter the product name in the search field.

Return to Search Tips

If you are not sure what you are looking for, you may browse the product categories by clicking on a “store” on the side navigation bar. All related items are grouped together in “departments” within the store. Also, for a comprehensive overview of all product categories offered on the site, you may click on the Product Directory link located on the side navigation bar.

Return to Search Tips

You may also type keywords into the SEARCH field if you have a general idea of the type of product you are looking for, but don’t know the specifics. The more general your keywords are, the more choices the search will find.

Return to Search Tips

* * *

  * Is It Safe To Use My Credit Card?
  * Use of Cookies.

Return to Help Index

Yes, shopping at www.intheswim.com is safe. You can access our Website home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data. If you wish to make a purchase on our website, it is necessary that you register with us and provide personal information so we may process your order. Personal data that you enter (for instance, address and credit card information) is transmitted to our website in a secure manner using a Security Certificate provided by the leading internet security firm, Verisign* and the most widely used security protocol, SSL (Secured Socket Layer**). Your personal information is then stored behind multiple layers of security on our website.

*Verisign, is the leading provider of Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) and digital certificate solutions used by websites and consumers to conduct secure communications and transactions over the internet and private networks. Be sure that you are ordering in a Secure Mode: When your browser is in a secure mode, you will notice an unbroken key or lock at the bottom left corner of the page.

**Secure Socket Layer (SSL) means your personal information, including credit card number, is encrypted and is readable only by our order-processing department. Browsers that allow for SSL technology: We recommend using Netscape version 3.02 or later, or Microsoft Internet Explorer version 3.02 or later. For AOL software users, version 4.0 or later is recommended.

Our website does not enable our visitors to communicate with other visitors or to post information to be accessed by others. Because of the dynamic nature of our website and the internet, cookies are used to enable visitors to place orders on our website. A cookie is a small file stored on your computer that identifies you to our website. No personal information, credit card data or marketing data is stored in the cookie. We collect the personal data that you volunteer when using our services. We use this data for marketing and customer service administration. We do not collect information about our visitors from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organizations.

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from unauthorized access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorized modification and accidental loss. All of our employees and data processors who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data. We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. If you have any further privacy concerns regarding the use of our website, please contact us at [webmaster@intheswim.com](mailto:webmaster@intheswim.com).

Return to Security & Privacy

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for www.intheswim.com. This notice applies solely to the information collected by this website. It will notify you of the following:

1\. What personally identifiable information is being collected from you through the website, how it is used and with whom it is shared  
2\. What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.  
3\. The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.  
4\. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

**Information Collection, Use, and Sharing**  
We are the sole owners of the information collected on this website. We only have access to collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone.

We will only use your information to respond to you regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than necessary to fulfill your request, e.g. to ship an order.

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this policy.

**Your Access to and Control over Information**  
You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number given on our website:

• See what data we have about you, if any  
• Change/correct any data we have about you  
• Have us delete any data we have about you  
• Express any concern you have about our use of your data

**Security**  
We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Whenever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data) that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for “https” at the beginning of the address of the webpage.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

**If you feel that we are not abiding by this Privacy Policy, you should contact us immediately via telephone at 1-800-374-1500 or via email at [customerservice@intheswim.com](mailto:customerservice@intheswim.com)**

In The Swim may use a browser feature known as a "cookie." Cookies are small files placed on your hard drive that assist In The Swim in providing you with a customized browsing experience. In The Swim uses cookies to provide you with the convenience of not having to reenter information, such as user IDs and passwords, multiple times during your visits to the In The Swim websites. Cookies can also be utilized to help In The Swim provide you with information targeted to your interests, based upon your prior browsing on In The Swim websites. You may Opt-Out of this advertising service by [Clicking Here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). The "help" section of the toolbar on most browsers will inform you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you upon the receipt of a new cookie, or how to disable the use of cookies completely. As the In The Swim websites have been designed to take advantage of the use of cookies, should you configure your browser to decline their use, certain features of the In The Swim websites may not function correctly and you may be required to reenter any user IDs and passwords more frequently.

Return to Security & Privacy

* * *

  * How Much Does Shipping Cost In The United States?
  * How Much Does Shipping Cost Outside Of The United States?
  * How Long Will It Take For My Product(s) To Arrive?
  * What If A Product Is On Backorder?
  * Oversized Delivery Items
  * Special Delivery Items
  * Custom Orders
  * Express Shipping
  * Can You Ship My Order To Another Address?
  * How Much Will The Tax Be?

Return to Help Index

Shipping is FREE for all orders in the 48 contiguous states, except for a handling charge. Items ordered together may be shipped separately, but you will only be charged for one handling fee. All prices include insurance against damage or theft.

**HANDLING TABLE**  
---  
**Orders up to $25.00** |  | **$8.99**  
**Orders $25.01 - $100.00** |  | **$9.99**  
**Orders over $100.00** |  | **$10.99**  
  
**Note:** Alaska, Hawaii & Puerto Rico residents, & military personnel shipping to an APO address, please call 1-800-288-7946 or email us at [customerservice@intheswim.com](mailto:customerservice@intheswim.com) with a list of the items you wish to purchase. Dr. Pool will contact you within 24 hours with the additional shipping charge. Some chemicals may not be available outside the 48 contiguous states and In The Swim cannot ship items exceeding 150 lbs. outside of the 48 contiguous states.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

If an order is to be shipped outside of the 48 contiguous United States, the customer is responsible for all shipping charges and all tariffs and/or import taxes imposed by the country to which the items are being shipped. In The Swim cannot ship chemicals or items exceeding 150 lbs. outside of the continental U.S.A. For international shipping charges, please call 1-800-288-7946 or email us at [customerservice@intheswim.com](mailto:customerservice@intheswim.com) with a list of the items you wish to purchase. Dr. Pool will contact you within 24 hours with the additional shipping charge.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

All in-stock orders placed Monday-Friday by 4pm CST are shipped the same day, and should arrive to you within 2 to 4 business days in the continental U.S.A. Most packages are shipped via Federal Express Home Delivery. In The Swim now delivers on Saturdays for no additional charge. If the combined weight of your order is 500 lbs. or more your order will be shipped via truckline with a 1 to 2 week delivery time. If you do not receive your purchase within 30 days, please notify us immediately.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

Products that are out of stock at the time of your order are indicated on the website next to the product listing. The estimated shipping date is also noted. You may place an order for an out-of-stock item, but it will be placed on backorder and shipped when it is received. If a product is on backorder for more than 30 days, you will be notified via a postcard in the mail.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

Some products on our website are noted as “Oversized Delivery.” These are generally items that are too big to be shipped through UPS, Federal Express or the Post Office. The estimated delivery time is noted next to each of these products and is usually between 1 week and 3 weeks. If you order an “Oversized Delivery” item, you will be contacted by the shipper within 24 hours of the scheduled delivery to set up an appointment for your merchandise.

**Note:** Refusal of delivery on an above-ground or in-ground pool will be subject to shipping and/or restocking fees. 

**Important!** Someone must be at the delivery location to receive these items, as they require a signature for delivery. You will be required to assist in moving the packages from the truck at the time of delivery.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

Some products on our website are noted as “Special Delivery.” These are products that take a little extra time in being delivered to you. The estimated delivery time is noted next to each product.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

Please call 1-800-288-7946.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

Please call 1-800-288-7946.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

Yes. When checking out you may specify another address to ship your products too.

Return to Shipping & Tax Information

**SALES TAX (if applicable)**  
---  
**Illinois Residents Add** |  | **7.75%**  
**New Jersey Residents Add** |  | **7.00%**  
**Georgia Residents Add** |  | **7.00%**  
**Texas Residents Add** |  | **8.25%**  
**Kentucky Residents Add** |  | **6.00%**  
**Nevada Residents Add** |  | **7.725%**  
**N. Carolina Residents Add** |  | **7.5%**  
**Florida Residents Add** |  | **7.0%**  
**Connecticut Residents Add** |  | **6.35%**  
 **Virginia Residents Add** |  | **6.00%**  
  
Return to Shipping & Tax Information

Discounts cannot be applied toward the purchase of select products by Aqua Creek, AquaCal, AquaPro, AquaProducts, Eco Blu, GAME, Global Lift Corp, Hayward, Inforesight, King Technology, Loop Loc, Main Access, Ocean Blue, Pentair, Pleatco, Pool Boy, Pool Patch LLC, SmartPool, Solaxx, Spa World Corp., STRONG, Strong Spas, Trojan Leisure Products, and Zodiac.

Site offers cannot be used in conjunction with any other offer and are not available on all products and are subject to restrictions and limitations. Prices and discounts are exclusive of applicable shipping charges and taxes. Offer not valid on previous orders. All prices on this web site are subject to change without notice. Discount does not apply on Inground Pool Kits. Discounts cannot be applied toward the purchase of select products.
